The Magic Blade
The Phoenix Town is quiet & deserted
Master Yen please
Master Yen
Third watch
The traveler shall die at the third watch
He'll die wherever he wanders
Dismissed
Our appointment is for the third watch
Now you're here
Of course for I am Yen Nan-fei
Last year you were defeated by me
Are you coming today to be killed?
Just now I enjoyed myself to the hilt
fearing that I might come to the end...
of my life tonight
Are you ready or not?
No need for I've come to kill
But I forget why I wanted to kill you!
It's I who want to kill you
Last year
I didn't believe you were
the fastest swordu...
I challenged you…
and was defeated by you
Fu Hung-hsueh is Fu Hung-hsueh
Earth Evil and Wood Evil
The two highest-paid underworld killers
Stay away. We want to kill Yen Nan-fei
You may not, his life belongs to me
How come they want to kill you?
Who's he?
Who cares? I only want to have a drink
It's an expensive restaurant
Everything here is 100% higher
Ever heard of Mr. Yu in the underworld
Did he hire Earth Evil and Wood Evil
Only he can afford such high-paid goons!
Right, but there must be more than two
At least several more men must be around
Look at those two beggars downstairs
That man is not blind
That woman's ferocious with her new shoes
And that men…
he stands there to cut off our retreat
That man is drinking quietly...
But he's saying when shall we start?
You can read his lips?
No, no
Give me back my cake
Uncle, hold it for me
What are you doing? You scared the kids!
Beware the kids!
I saved your life!
Grandma, the two men upstairs bullied us
She's Devil Grandma
Another famous underworld killer!
Devil Grandma's really ghastly
Why does Mr. Yu want to kill you
You mean Us
Dose he want to kill me too?
Where are you going now?
To get drinks of course
Where are we?
This is the Ming Yueh Restaurant
Ming Yueh Restaurant?
Have you heard of Ming Yueh-hsin?
She's a well-known beauty
She has many admirers
This is her house
Mr. Yen come in please
What are you doing?
Miss prepared something special...
As she was expecting distinguished guests
The wine, sir
That's exactly what I need
It was poisoned!
The man who died outside is Tang Hsiang...
of the notorious Tang family
They only come here to poison someone
You're really sharp, sir
Mr. Yen, who on earth is he?
He's Fu Hung-hsueh who challenged me...
to a duel at Chung Yang Festival
Did he want to kill you?
Yes, but now he has saved my life...
for the third time
No one shall kill him for he's mine
Not even Mr. Yu?
Do you know who Mr. Yu is?
Yes, a romantic and wealthy swordsman
No
He now controls the swordplay world...
and wants to dominate it
He's only afraid of three things
Which things?
Yen Nan-fei and you
And?
Peacock Dart-the No.1 weapon...
in strategy
Peacock Dart is dreadful, but it's a weapon
And you're living beings
Last year I tried hard...
to kill Mr. Yu for the sake of the Dart
That's what you called
the outstanding thing
I hear that none can enter it except one
Who?
You
Because you saved the chief's life
If Peacock Dart should fall into Yu's hands
The wicked will dominate,
the sword-play world
What if it should fall into my hand?
Then we'll unite to eliminate the evil
It seems I have no other choice
You should take action as soon as possible
Mr. Yu please
Bring in Devil Grandma
Mr. Yu
Grandma, how are things in Phoenix Lane?
Earth Eviland Wood Evilwere killed
I used Thunder Bullet to get away
Fu Hung-hsueh's really fierce. You go first
Yes, sir
Madam, where's Fu Hung-hsueh now?
He's heading northeast...
Probably for the Peacock mansion
We must go and get the Peacock Dart now
Shih, Hua, Chin, Chi, Chien
I am here
You must teach Hung-hsueh a lesson
Yes, sir
Look
You're early but others are earlier
The flowers fall and the swallows die
The painting sounds like a warning to us
Right. The room's littered with the dead!
Chess after poem, chin and painting
It's a hopeless chess game
Actually it can still be saved...
by taking chariot with cannon
Fling it away
Advance horse
Move chariot
Are you looking for me?
Are you Chi?
No, we're his men
Do you bear me a grudge?
No, killing's not necessarily due to grudge
Then for what?
Pleasure
What sort of pleasure?
Several hundred thousand taels of silver
I'm happy I can give you pleasure...
but your pleasure won't last long
Why?
And the dead cannot rejoice
Did you hear what he said?
Yes
Who are you?
I've also come to kill you
Get up
Why should I?
Because I want to take your seat
Don't keep your weapon in a parcel
You may need it for killing!
They say you're a prophet...
but this time you're mistaken
You'd better give up
Why?
Because I don't kill an unarmed woman
First, I'm not a woman
Second, I use this hand to kill
It is my weapon
I told you to give up. Go away
Why didn't you kill him?
It wasn't necessary
I cut off his hand, which is his weapon
On guard!
Don't pursue him
Why not?
He must be Chien
Shih, Hua, Chin, Chi, Chien
Yu knew we had taken action
Then let's get Peacock Dart quickly
No visitors are allowed to Peacock Mansion
Please go away
But he's Fu Hung-hsueh...
who saved your master's life
Please
Mr. Fu, my man didn't know it was you
Please excuse us
Don't mention it
Please sit down
Please
They kill the antelope for his horns...
and dig a grave for the treasure
We take precautions...
to protect our Peacock Dart
36 swordsmen came for the dart
And none of them returned alive
That's why we've been
able to keep it intact
you must be here for Peacock Dart
How do you know, sir?
No one's ever come here for another reason
Yes, we have come here to borrow...
your Peacock Dart to eliminate the evil Yu
After it's done, we'll return it to you
You've come at the right time
Show him the letter
Yes
Deliver Peacock Dart within 10 days
or there will be bloodshed, Yu
We got the letter yesterday
Recently many strange things have happened
We've lost many swordsmen
We're really at our wits end
Gentlemen, please come with me
This door has five locks.
The 5 keys are kept by
5 different people...
You said there's five locks
How about the remaining key?
The remaining key…
is kept by my daughter Yu-cheng
Daddy
Come and meet Mr. Fu and Mr. Yen
Mr. Fu, Mr. Yen
Miss Chiu
For many years...
no outsiders have ever come here
You may wonder...
why we're willing...
to lend you the Peacock Dart
I was wondering...
How good and bad swordsmen...
are facing a last-ditch battle
Peacock dart will decide our fate
To avoid it falling into Yu's hands...
I'll give it to you
Yu-cheng
Yes, daddy
Peacock dart's inside the box
What are you doing?
I'll check it for you
No need, I'll check it myself
Stay where you are
Mr. Yu has arranged for me to stay here…
for many years for the sake of...
getting the Peacock Dart
Mr. Fu, I should thank you
Had you not come here, I'd never've made it
I was just wondering...
why Yu's letter was received today
Don't come over
Move!
Tell our men to dress in white
Yes
I have the key
Stop
You think you can get out of here?
You think you can take away Peacock Dart?
Why not, now that I've got the box!
When all of you are dead...
I'll certainly get out of the mansion
Stop
One more move and I'll use the dart
Gentlemen, please stop
This is our business. Let me handle it
Kung Sun-tao open the box and look
Do you see? It's empty
It's an empty box which men of the...
underworld have been dreaming to get
What?
You said there's no
Peacock Dart in the world
This is the real Peacock Dart
It has been lying here...
since we built the mansion
The most secret place...
is the most unsecret
The safest place...
is also the most unsafe
Even this box which has been...
kept so secret can be obtained by you
Incredible! You're trying to scare me!
Mr. Fu, have you heard of the dart's power?
Yes, I have
The dart when hurled emits mysterious
and beautiful rays and the victim dies...
in a mysterious way
And no one is immune to it
It really lives up to its reputation
Sir, your arm
The sword was poisoned
Daddy, are you alright?
I'm finished. Mr. Fu...
after what has happened...
Yu will not spare our mansion
So I'm ordering an evacuation
Our mansion will be no more
Daddy
My daughter, Yu-cheng has no next of kin
Please take care of her for me
Only you can save her from...
being killed by Yu
I was indirectly responsible for all this
I'll do my best to protect Miss Chiu
I'll give the Peacock Dart to you
Only two feathers are left that can be used
You must use it only in cases of emergency
I know
Mr. Chiu Daddy
Somehow I have the feeling we've been
tricked into coming here
Impossible. No one knew...
we were coming here
Oh, yes. Ming Yueh-hsin did
Ming Yueh-hsin, Ming Yueh-hsin
A bright moon has no heart
Who are you?
You are Yu Chin-one of Mr. Yu's
five Fighters
Why didn't you ask...
what has happened to Ming Yueh-hsin?
No need when you're here
I hear that you never fight...
with an unarmed woman
You're not unarmed
Mr. Yu says if you wish,
to save Yueh-hsin…
you must hand over the dart at once
So that you may use it
to kill all of us
To find Yueh-hsin you must find Mr. Yu
I don't think Yueh-hsin has betrayed us
She must have been caught by them
What shall we do now?
We'll find a hiding place...
For Miss Chiu first
Then we'll go and find Mr. Yu
What? In the Tu Village?
Yes, after leaving Ming Yueh Restaurant…
they headed northwest
There are few villages in the northwest…
except the Tu Village
Madam! Why do they go to the Tu Village?
Because Fu Hung-hsueh's only bosom friend
Tu Shih-chi lives there
Ku Chi
Yes
Intercept them at the Yueh Embankment
There's still a distance to the Tu Village
and there are no towns in between
better stop and get something to eat first
aren't you afraid they may recognize us?
Let me get something for you
What will you have, gentlemen?
Anything will do
Old lady, I want to get something to eat
Good, have some cakes first,
then stewed hand
That's roasted human meat there
Which do you want?
Miss Chiu, what happened?
Look, look
Devil Grandma
Mr. Yu's remarkably well-informed
Look
Life is like a chess game
Since you're here. Why not join in it?
If I am not mistaken...
you must to one of Yu's Fighters
Chi, Ku Wu-chi
Yes, you're right
A smiling killer. To kill, find Ku Wu-chi
That is underworld hear say only
Actually I like chess better than killing
How about joining me for a game tonight?
Sorry, we don't play chess
But you must because
you're already involved
What are they doing?
They are setting a chess formation
Our retreat has been cut off
They've chariots, horses and soldiers
We've got only two soldiers
Yes, we're at a disadvantage
Wait, after they die...
don't mutilate their bodies
I need them for cooking
Devil Grandma. What's your special today?
Roasted Yen Nan-fei
Fried Fu Hung-hsueh
Braised Chiu Yu-cheng
Cannon
Horse
Chariot
Want some more of my cakes?
Watch out, it's her Thunder Bullet
I don't serve the same dish each time!
Soldiers
Double cannon
How about a flying elephant?
Better you go out yourself
Chariot and horse
There're 30-40 men here
We must find a way out
Can you see the horse?
I'll turn back to attack Ku Wu-chi...
and take the horse and flee
Miss Chiu, wait here
After them
Ku Wu-chi, it's the worst game of your life
Bring the horse
Dismount
Let's separate. You go to Tu Village first
Your hand!
It's alright
I'll get some water to wash it for you
Miss Chiu! Miss Chiu
You tried to poison me!
No, no, I didn't
I'll kill you. You...
No, I didn't do it
I'll kill you! Women! Women!
I didn't do it, I didn't
No need to get up
The incense will make you lose your sense
Even Fu Hung-hsueh will be powerless
How did you do it?
I put poison into the upper stream...
of the brook outside
A good chess player always knows...
His opponent's next move
Light the incense
Yes
The drug's in the form of a coil of incense
Once it burns out it's ineffective
Therefore, you must kill him...
before it burns out
Get the Peacock Dart from him
Have you got it?
There's nothing on him
Could it be with that girl?
No, I watched them all the time
He didn't give it to her...
he even tried to kill her
Your blood's delicious
Wait, Do you want to suck his blood...
or get his peacock Dart?
The incense has almost burnt out
I'll count up to three
If you don't tell, I'll torture you
One
Two
Speak up
Three
Wait
The Peacock Dart's here
If you want it first release Mr. Fu
Miss Chiu
Luckily I hit his sinus
Now he still can't move
Search the girl
Yes
There's nothing on her
Don't make a move
Why not?
If you do, you'll die first
Let's see how you can kill me
I've practiced 20 years
to move the sinus in my body by 1 inch
So your paralisation did not work
Fu Hung-hsueh's Fu Hung-hsueh
I want to ask you a last question
What is it?
Where on earth is the Peacock Dart?
When I was poisoned, I know there were...
men around, so I hid it in the room...
and pretended to be chasing Miss Chiu
the dart was beside you all the time
no wonder Fu Hung-hsueh is rated No.1
in the List of Swordsmen
Miss Chiu, a while ago...
I told you to flee
Why did you come back?
Didn't you know they might kill you also?
Yes
Then why?
I feared you might be killed by them
There's not a soul in Peacock mansion
If you were killed, I would be alone
Are you afraid of loneliness?
Yes
But I get used to it
of the country alone with my sword
Without friends or love
cI've wandered over the length and breadth
For almost 10 years...
15 years ago
I pursuit of fame and wealth left home
whose garden exploded with yellow flowers…
After hard practice. I challenged many...
toddlers and eventually became popular
But then I returned to my home town
My lover had gone away
I heard that she had got married
The flowered garden was no more
On the wall were inscribed the characters
In lust of power and
wealth the hair grey goes,
On mountains old the pine & bamboo grows
For over 10 years you've been wandering…
alone with your sword
hunting for that girl?
One thing I want to tell you is...
The more popular, the more lonely you are
At the top of career you've no friends
This flower may not be as pretty as that…
in your home town, but it's also yellow
Thank you, Miss Chiu
Before, I only owed my home town a favor
Now I own the Chius' gratitude for 2 lives
First, you saved my life
Second, your daddy died because of me
Coming, coming
I'm looking for Tu Shih-chi
Please come in
Is this the place?
Is something wrong?
Nothing
Mr. Fu, so you're here.
Come in and sit down
You are...
We've never met, but I'm
Shih-chi's newlywed
Please come in
Mr. Yen came already
My husband asked me to prepare some food
Please sit down, please sit down
Where's Shih-chi?
He went to buy wine with Mr. Yen
He wanted you not to wait for him
Please have tea
I'll go & get something. Please
Shih-chi was injured as a boy
and therefore is impotent
That woman's ferocious
Tu Shih-chi
Who are you?
You're early but others are earlier
Chi
Right
Your friend's in Tien Lung Temple
They say I'm a mad monk
Actually the world's full of mad men
Some rush to get killed
They're madder than I
Sir. May I ask who painted these?
I did
I know you're looking for them
So I painted them
How do you know?
I know everything
Chiu Yu-cheng was kidnapped in Tu Village
Swordsman Yen Nan-fei was killed...
in the Tu Village
What? Is Yen Nan-fei dead?
Yes, he's dead
All men must die...
But not every man dies in the same day
Yen died in the Tu Village
You'll die here
Who are you? Where do you come from?
I'm myself. I come from nowhere
Don't play the fool. Youre one of...
Yu's Five Fighters, Wu Hua
You're right
I am Wu Hua
Miss Chiu
What do you want?
Get all of them out quickly
Alright. Come out
Miss Chiu. Come out, Miss Chiu
Alright
Fu Hung-hsueh is Fu Hung-hsueh
but Miss Chiu's not Miss Chiu. Fight
Wu Hua, it's your turn
Alright, come on
Fu Hung-hsueh, do you know what it is?
It's a character Chien
Yes
Here are 20 No.1 swordsmen who have...
All come to kill you
Can you kill me?
Come and try
Don't run away
Come over
Draw your sword
Why should I?
Don't you want to kill me?
I'll spare you
Wait. I won't spare you
Don't come over
Why?
Frankly...
you can't kill me
Come and try
Because you'd never kill an unarmed man
Right
You can't kill me...
because my sword is a fake...
and I don't know martial art
I was only hired to scare you
Who hired you?
Boss, boss
Sword!
Fu Hung-hsueh, see you later!
It's cold
Got any wine?
Yes, yes
Bring me a warm pot
Good
Here you are, sir
Sir, will you buy me a bowl of noodles?
After you've eaten. I'll sleep with you
Give her a bowl of noodles
Give her another bowl
Are you very hungry?
I have not eaten for three days
But don't worry, I'll pay you back...
by sleeping with you twice
Noodles
Thank you. Come with me, sir
She's sick
How do you know?
She has no parents
For a living, she...
I didn't want to cheat. I was too hungry
Forget it. Take this & buy medicines
Why?
It's a debt the world owes you. Take it
Go home
What's your name?
My name!
Never mind. Just call me Yellow Flower!
Yellow Flower
What a terrible yellow flower!
Who are you?
So it's you. I've heard that Mr.Yu
has 5 fighters; Shih, Hua, Chin, Chi, Chien
I've seen four of them
You must be the fifth one
Yes, I am Hsiao Chien
Hsiao Chien
Invincible, and a killer of many
And?
And cold-blooded. Sword
You should have stabbed me in the back
My name is not shameless
Yellow Flower
Miss! Miss!
Who is he?
He came to kill you also
To find Mr. Yu, go to Tien Wai Mansion
Miss! Miss!
Miss
Where's my yellow flower?
This is the prettiest flower I've ever seen
Miss
Old gentleman
Find a clean place to bury her
The Tien Wai Village
Mr. Fu arrived
Mr. Fu please
Please
This is Mr. Yu's exercising room. Wait
Wait. Madam will come to meet you
Please
Madam is here
Ming Yueh-hsin
The bright moon has no heart
I am Yu's wife
That why he know everything
Where is he?
He said he'll see you tomorrow
We've arranged accommodation for you
Please stay here tonight
Ask Madam to come out at once
Madam
Is the water ready?
Yes. Madam. See if it's alright
Just right
The ancestral tablet of Fu Hung-hsueh
Mr. Fu, please sit down
What's the idea of your taking a bath...
the coffin upstairs & the food here?
This means you only have two choices
One is to enjoy money & power here
Another is to become a corpse in a coffin
Our master said me must enjoy himself
to the hilt on his last day
you'll need drinks now
After all, you're a man
How do I compare with those two women?
What do you mean by that?
Our master wants to offer me
And half of the fortune here
for your Peacock Dart
When I am naked, as I am now...
few men can resist the temptation
I suppose I must be one of those few
But the other girl you've got...
can be exchanged for my Peacock Dart
Is she better than me?
Don't forget, my other reason for coming
here is to see Miss Chiu
Chiu Yu-cheng
Over there
Mr. Fu
Miss Chiu
Fu Hung-hsueh, if you don't hand over...
the Peacock Dart before dawn...
she'll die here even if you should...
get out of the Tien Wai Mansion
Mr. Fu, why did you come here?
To look for you
What about tomorrow?
Tomorrow there will be a last duel...
between me and Mr. Yu
But if we don't give him the dart tonight…
he may never show his face tomorrow
You want to give him the dart
Yes, but your father told me to consult...
you first before it's used.
Master, here's Peacock Dart
I know that only the two feathers...
that can be plucked are real
I know
Fu Hung-hsueh's Fu Hung-hsueh.
He never lies
Why did he give me the real Peacock Dart?
He wanted you to release Yu-cheng first
Go! Now that I know where you are...
I'll come back for you
You must
I will
Please wait, sir
Mr. Yu has the dart, but dares not show up
You're wrong. I've been waiting here
Are you alone?
Yes, I am along
Why didn't you bring some more men?
Why did you come alone?
Because you're Fu Hung-hsueh. I'm Mr. Yu
Either you live or I live
It's between the two of us only
It doesn't concern a third party
The swordplay world's an independent state
There can be only one ruler; you or me
Good, but before the last dual...
I want to ask you a question
What is it?
Where's Yen Nan-fei?
Didn't he die in the Tu Village?
No, you're wrong. He's not dead
He's still here
Yen Nan-fei, take off your mask
How did you know I didn't
die in Tu Village?
Probably you forget that no one on earth
Except Fu Hung-hsueh can kill you
You couldn't have died if I didn't kill you
I know there's ambushed
You couldn't have come to kill me alone
Anything you don't know?
I don't know whether or not you can kill me
Sword
One has died, and they are only four left
4 have died, and you're the only one left
What's the difference from last year?
Last year's duel decided only the winner
Today's duel decides who will live
Stay where you are
The duel between Fu and Yen has ended
I only want to die by my own sword
Congratulations!
From now on everything here belongs to you
Where's Yu?
Didn't you kill him just now?
No, he was not Yu
How do you know he was not Yu?
Because he didn't have the Peacock Dart
Peacock Dart is a last resort
If he were Yu...
he would have used it to kill me
You really want to see Yu?
What do you see in the mirror?
Myself
No, it's Master Yu
Master Yu is only an image
It represents wealth and power
Whoever's best in martial art is Yu
You killed Yen Nan-fei today...
so you're Master Yu
For how long?
Until there's someone in the underworld...
who can outrival you...
Then I must try to eliminate him
or I'll be another Yen Nan-fei
Right, whoever's the strongest is the master
Where are you going?
I want to live...
and I take no interest in money and power
Wait, you're now Master Yu
You can't give up
Why?
Because I want you to be Master Yu
You're the real Master Yu
Right, I am Master Yu
If you hadn't seen my Peacock Dart
Your would have seen my grey hair which…
has growth with fighting
for money and power
For 30 years I've been worrying about...
my leadership
I want to dominate the swordplay world...
forever and ever
Certainly no one would give up
his past glory
Unfortunately I'm getting old and weak...
unlike over 30 years ago...
when I killed 78 swordsmen in one night
So you want to find a right-hand man
Yes, I found Yen Nan-fei
Unfortunately he was defeated by you
Then I gave him one year to kill you
I didn't allow him to stab you in the back
That explains why he didn't do it...
when he had many chances to do so
For I only want a real swordsman
Whether it's you or Yen makes no difference
So his death means nothing to you
Of course, since there's someone better…
in martial art than him
I may have beaten Yen Nan-fei...
but I don't want to work for Master Yu
Why not?
I don't want to grow old with grey hair…
for the sake of money and power
Nor do I want to get killed someday
If you don't take the place...
You'll never be Fu Hung-hsueh
Why?
Because I have the Peacock Dart
Are you sure you can kill me?
Certainly
I tested the power of the dart today
You can't escape it within 50 feet
So you've only one real feather left
One is enough to kill you
Try it
Fu Hung-hsueh
The Peacock Coat was givern to me by...
Miss Chiu last night
The secret was revealed to me by...
her father before his death
He told me it could withstand the dart...
and counter it
Now you understand...
why I insisted on seeing her last night
and agreed to give you the dart today
Fu Hung-hsueh's Fu Hung-hsueh
But Master Yu's also Master Yu
The chair and traps were designed by me…
in case of emergency
There's no way for you to kill me
After I recover, I'll tell you...
when the last duel will be
Where are you going? Can't you see...
money and power are waiting for you?
Reserve them for those who seek death only!